<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howard Liu | Liu Research Lab</title>
    <link>https://howardhliu.com/author/howard-liu/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://howardhliu.com/author/howard-liu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Howard Liu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Howard Liu.</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://howardhliu.com/images/icon_hub8f4bda36930b2d334c7b95ed0c23925_8964_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Howard Liu</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/author/howard-liu/</link>
    </image>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
thor/howard-liu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance Studies</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/publication/surveillance-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://howardhliu.com/publication/surveillance-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Surveillance is a critical tool of political and social control, employed by both authoritarian and democratic regimes to monitor populations, suppress dissent, and maintain political stability. Despite its widespread use, surveillance remains an understudied and contested concept across disciplines, with political science, sociology, and multi-disciplinary surveillance research offering distinct perspectives on its nature, methods, and consequences. This chapter synthesizes existing research and introduces a new framework that categorizes surveillance methods based on two key dimensions: visibility (overt vs. covert) and interface (human vs. technological). By integrating insights from different disciplines, the chapter develops a layered model of surveillance targets and a typology of surveillance methods that highlight the strategic choices regimes make. It further examines the agency problems arising from delegated surveillance, the causes driving state and corporate surveillance, and the consequences of surveillance on dissent and repression. Our analysis underscores the dual function of surveillance as both a deterrent and a potential catalyst for resistance. By bridging disciplinary divides, this chapter offers a comprehensive framework for analyzing the evolving role of surveillance in contemporary governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;監控研究：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;監控是實現政治與社會控制的關鍵工具，不論是在威權政體還是民主政體中，都被廣泛用於監視民眾、壓制反對力量、維護政權穩定。儘管監控的應用已相當普遍，其概念在學術界仍屬於研究不足的階段，理論概念也充滿諸多爭議。政治學、社會學以及跨學科的監控研究，各自從不同角度詮釋監控的本質、手段與影響。本章在整合既有研究基礎上，提出一套新的分析框架，從兩個關鍵維度——可見性（公開與隱蔽）以及介面形式（人力與科技）——對各種監控手段進行分類。透過跨學科的觀點融合，本文提出一個層次化的監控對象模型，以及一套監控手段的類型分析，來突顯出政權在選擇監控策略時所面臨的策略考量。另外，本文亦進一步探討在委託式監控中所出現的代理問題、國家與企業推動監控擴張的背後動因，以及監控如何影響異議行為與政治壓制。我們的分析指出，監控同時具備震攝與激發反抗力量的兩種相反的功能。整體而言，我们的分析透過打破學科壁壘與觀點分歧，提供一個更為全面、系統的理論架構，以理解監控在當代政治治理中所扮演的多重角色與演變趨勢。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citation:&lt;/br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.degruyterbrill.com/document/isbn/9783111298559/html?lang=en&amp;amp;srsltid=AfmBOopHl8HL30aezSpIB2_fC-iml02FmZzo0cPshSdROEm2xLhNHrKz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Liu, Howard and Deki Peldon. In &lt;em&gt;The Handbook of Political Control.&lt;/em&gt; De Gruyter, 2025.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea Human Rights Abuses</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/project/north-korea-hr-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://howardhliu.com/project/north-korea-hr-proj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law or the Career? Autocratic Judiciaries, Strategic Sentencing, and Political Repression</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/publication/authoritarian-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://howardhliu.com/publication/authoritarian-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do judges sometimes act against autocrats’ will, even without judicial independence and tenure security? Contrary to the theory of strategic defection under weak governments, we argue that this behavior can also emerge under strong governments with lax monitoring. When autocrats primarily monitor severe political cases, judges can strategically downplay case severity to avoid oversight, thereby increasing judicial autonomy and the rule of law. Yet, these adjustments will be carefully calibrated–sufficient to evade scrutiny but not too drastic to trigger autocrats’ suspicions and incur sanctions against judges. We test this expectation with new data on Taiwan’s military trials during authoritarian rule, finding that judges tend not to issue sentences above a review threshold after its introduction. Sentence reductions are mostly moderate, affecting cases where sentences can fall slightly above or below the threshold under judges’ discretion. These findings have implications for understanding state repression and judicial agency in nondemocracies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;為什麼在缺乏司法獨立和任期保障的條件下，法官有時還會違背獨裁者的意願？與既有理論假設弱政府中會有戰略性叛逃的理論相反，我們認為這種行為也可能發生在監管鬆懈的強政府之下。當獨裁者主要關注重大政治案件時，法官可以策略性地降低案件的嚴重性，從而增強司法自主性和法治的實行。然而，這種判決嚴重度的調整通常會保持在適當的範圍內，既足以規避審查，又不至於過分激進以至於招致獨裁者的猜疑和懲罰。我們利用台灣威權統治時期的軍事審判新數據來驗證這一假設，結果顯示，引入監督門檻後，法官判決被告超過監督門檻的概率降低。這些判刑的減輕通常是適度的，根據法官的裁量權涉及可能略高於審查門檻的案件進行輕微的向下調整。這些發現對於理解威權政權下國家的鎮壓力度及司法機構的行為具有重要的啟示意義。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
