<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yi-Ting Wang | Liu Research Lab</title>
    <link>https://howardhliu.com/author/yi-ting-wang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://howardhliu.com/author/yi-ting-wang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Yi-Ting Wang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Howard Liu.</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://howardhliu.com/images/icon_hub8f4bda36930b2d334c7b95ed0c23925_8964_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Yi-Ting Wang</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/author/yi-ting-wang/</link>
    </image>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
or/yi-ting-wang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Secret: Surveillance, Informant Networks, and the Protection of Informants in Authoritarian Regimes</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/publication/informantprotection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://howardhliu.com/publication/informantprotection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authoritarian regimes rely heavily on informant networks to infiltrate and surveil dissident organizations. While the role of informants in state repression is well-documented, existing research often overlooks how secret police use the intelligence gathered from informants without compromising their identities. In this article, we examine the conditions under which secret police agencies seek to protect informants from exposure. We argue that agencies face a tradeoff between the risks of exposing informants and the costs of implementing protection, often prioritizing protection for informants who are deeply embedded in dissident networks and provide rare, high-value intelligence. Using declassified surveillance reports from 1970s Taiwan, we find that protection is most likely when informants are close to well-connected dissidents, interact with behind-the-scenes activists, or provide sensitive information about internal conflicts. Deeply embedded informants offer high-value intelligence but face greater risks of exposure, making them especially worth protecting. These findings contribute to research on surveillance and repression by showing how secret police manage the risks of informant exposure while leveraging human intelligence to counter dissent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「應用時，請報密」：威權政府下的秘密監控、異議份子網絡、與線民保護計畫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;威權政權往往高度依賴線民網絡來滲透並監控異議份子。雖然線民在國家鎮壓中的角色早已被廣泛研究，但既有文獻往往忽略了一個重要的問題：祕密警察如何在不曝光線民身分的情況下運用他們蒐集的情報。本文探討祕密警察在何種情況下會致力於保護線民免於曝光。我們認為，情報機構在行動時必須在兩種風險間權衡：一是線民可能被暴露的風險，二是保護線民所需的成本。在權衡曝光風險與保護成本的情況下，祕密警察會優先選擇保護那些深度滲入異議網絡、能提供稀有且高價值情報的線民。本文透過分析臺灣1970年代解密的監控檔案來檢證此觀點。我們發現，當線民與人脈廣泛的異議人士關係密切、與潛藏在地下的幕後行為者有接觸，或能提供關於內部衝突的敏感資訊時，他們最有可能受到保護。這意味深度滲透的線民能提供高價值情報供秘密警察使用，但同時又面臨更高的曝光風險，因此更值得被保護。這份研究結果有助於我们理解秘密監控與鎮壓的運作，並揭示祕密警察如何在運用人力情報打擊異議時，同時權衡線民被曝光的風險。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citation: &lt;/br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liu, Howard, Ching-Hsuan Su, and Yi-Ting Wang. &amp;ldquo;Keeping It Secret: Surveillance, Informant Networks, and the Protection of Informants in Authoritarian Regimes.&amp;rdquo; Journal of Peace Research, Forthcoming&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law or the Career? Autocratic Judiciaries, Strategic Sentencing, and Political Repression</title>
      <link>https://howardhliu.com/publication/authoritarian-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://howardhliu.com/publication/authoritarian-court/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do judges sometimes act against autocrats’ will, even without judicial independence and tenure security? Contrary to the theory of strategic defection under weak governments, we argue that this behavior can also emerge under strong governments with lax monitoring. When autocrats primarily monitor severe political cases, judges can strategically downplay case severity to avoid oversight, thereby increasing judicial autonomy and the rule of law. Yet, these adjustments will be carefully calibrated–sufficient to evade scrutiny but not too drastic to trigger autocrats’ suspicions and incur sanctions against judges. We test this expectation with new data on Taiwan’s military trials during authoritarian rule, finding that judges tend not to issue sentences above a review threshold after its introduction. Sentence reductions are mostly moderate, affecting cases where sentences can fall slightly above or below the threshold under judges’ discretion. These findings have implications for understanding state repression and judicial agency in nondemocracies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;為什麼在缺乏司法獨立和任期保障的條件下，法官有時還會違背獨裁者的意願？與既有理論假設弱政府中會有戰略性叛逃的理論相反，我們認為這種行為也可能發生在監管鬆懈的強政府之下。當獨裁者主要關注重大政治案件時，法官可以策略性地降低案件的嚴重性，從而增強司法自主性和法治的實行。然而，這種判決嚴重度的調整通常會保持在適當的範圍內，既足以規避審查，又不至於過分激進以至於招致獨裁者的猜疑和懲罰。我們利用台灣威權統治時期的軍事審判新數據來驗證這一假設，結果顯示，引入監督門檻後，法官判決被告超過監督門檻的概率降低。這些判刑的減輕通常是適度的，根據法官的裁量權涉及可能略高於審查門檻的案件進行輕微的向下調整。這些發現對於理解威權政權下國家的鎮壓力度及司法機構的行為具有重要的啟示意義。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
